var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "answer": "(of) Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "ib'rāhīma",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ عَنْ ضَيْفِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 69,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِبْلِيسَ",
        "answer": "Iblis",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 9,
        "tlit": "ib'līsa",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا إِبْلِيسَ أَبَىٰ أَنْ يَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْلِيس",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْلِيس",
        "waznEnglish": "Iblis",
        "waznTlit": "ib'līs",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَا إِبْلِيسُ",
        "answer": "O Iblis",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 9,
        "tlit": "yāib'līsu",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا إِبْلِيسُ مَا لَكَ أَلَّا تَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْلِيس",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْلِيس",
        "waznEnglish": "Iblis",
        "waznTlit": "ib'līs",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبَىٰ",
        "answer": "He refused",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 11,
        "tlit": "abā",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا إِبْلِيسَ أَبَىٰ أَنْ يَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ب ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to refuse",
        "waznTlit": "hamza bā yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَأْتِينَا",
        "answer": "you bring to us",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "tatīnā",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ مَا تَأْتِينَا بِالْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنْ كُنْتَ مِنَ الصَّادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 264,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَأْتِيهِمْ",
        "answer": "came to them",
        "pcklId": "112",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "yatīhim",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَأْتِيهِمْ مِنْ رَسُولٍ إِلَّا كَانُوا بِهِ يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 264,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَتَيْنَاكَ",
        "answer": "And we have come to you",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "wa-ataynāka",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 64,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَتَيْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ وَإِنَّا لَصَادِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 264,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَأْتِيَكَ",
        "answer": "comes to you",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "yatiyaka",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 99,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاعْبُدْ رَبَّكَ حَتَّىٰ يَأْتِيَكَ الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 264,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "And We gave them",
        "pcklId": "400",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "waātaynāhum",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 81,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ آيَاتِنَا فَكَانُوا عَنْهَا مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آتَيْنَاكَ",
        "answer": "We have given you",
        "pcklId": "401",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "ātaynāka",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 87,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ آتَيْنَاكَ سَبْعًا مِنَ الْمَثَانِي وَالْقُرْآنَ الْعَظِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَآتِيَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely coming",
        "pcklId": "537",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "laātiyatun",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ السَّاعَةَ لَآتِيَةٌ فَاصْفَحِ الصَّفْحَ الْجَمِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتِي",
        "waznEnglish": "coming",
        "waznTlit": "ātī",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجَلَهَا",
        "answer": "its term",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 19,
        "tlit": "ajalahā",
        "frequency": 56,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا تَسْبِقُ مِنْ أُمَّةٍ أَجَلَهَا وَمَا يَسْتَأْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجَل",
        "waznEnglish": "term",
        "waznTlit": "ajal",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحَدٌ",
        "answer": "anyone",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 20,
        "tlit": "aḥadun",
        "frequency": 85,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَلْتَفِتْ مِنْكُمْ أَحَدٌ وَامْضُوا حَيْثُ تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ح د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحَد",
        "waznEnglish": "one, anyone",
        "waznTlit": "aḥad",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 74,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ",
        "answer": "So, seized them",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "fa-akhadhathumu",
        "frequency": 273,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 73,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُشْرِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take, to seize",
        "waznTlit": "akhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 127,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ",
        "answer": "But seized them",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "fa-akhadhathumu",
        "frequency": 273,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 83,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take, to seize",
        "waznTlit": "akhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 127,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَأْخِرُونَ",
        "answer": "(can) delay it",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "yastakhirūna",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا تَسْبِقُ مِنْ أُمَّةٍ أَجَلَهَا وَمَا يَسْتَأْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَأْخِرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to delay, to postpone",
        "waznTlit": "yastakhiru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آخَرَ",
        "answer": "another",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "ākhara",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَأْخِرِينَ",
        "answer": "the later ones",
        "pcklId": "249",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-mus'takhirīna",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْنَا الْمُسْتَقْدِمِينَ مِنْكُمْ وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْنَا الْمُسْتَأْخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَـْٔخِرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "later ones",
        "waznTlit": "mus'takhirīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِخْوَانًا",
        "answer": "(they will be) brothers",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 23,
        "tlit": "ikh'wānan",
        "frequency": 96,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخ",
        "waznEnglish": "brother",
        "waznTlit": "akh",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 75,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذْ",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "wa-idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "So, when",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": 409,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 409,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذًا",
        "answer": "then",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 28,
        "tlit": "idhan",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذًا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِذًا",
        "waznEnglish": "then",
        "waznTlit": "idhan",
        "waznType": "Particle (Surprise particle)",
        "waznFreq": 31,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "And the earth",
        "pcklId": "170",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍa",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ مَدَدْنَاهَا وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ وَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا مِنْ كُلِّ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍi",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ وَلَأُغْوِيَنَّهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "172",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍa",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَأْكُلُوا",
        "answer": "(to) eat",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "yakulū",
        "frequency": 109,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to eat, to consume",
        "waznTlit": "akala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 93,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "203",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَهْلَكْنَا مِنْ قَرْيَةٍ إِلَّا وَلَهَا كِتَابٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "204",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "205",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَأْتِيهِمْ مِنْ رَسُولٍ إِلَّا كَانُوا بِهِ يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "206",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "207",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "208",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "209",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا إِبْلِيسَ أَبَىٰ أَنْ يَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "210",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَكَ مِنْهُمُ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "211",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ إِلَّا مَنِ اتَّبَعَكَ مِنَ الْغَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "212",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "213",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ إِنَّا لَمُنَجُّوهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "214",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا امْرَأَتَهُ قَدَّرْنَا إِنَّهَا لَمِنَ الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "648",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " رُبَمَا يَوَدُّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَوْ كَانُوا مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "(to) whom",
        "pcklId": "649",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "Those who",
        "pcklId": "650",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 91,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ جَعَلُوا الْقُرْآنَ عِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "Those who",
        "pcklId": "651",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَلِيمُ",
        "answer": "the most painful",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 60,
        "tlit": "l-alīmu",
        "frequency": 75,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ عَذَابِي هُوَ الْعَذَابُ الْأَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "painful",
        "waznTlit": "alīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَٰهًا",
        "answer": "god",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ilāhan",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهَ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "1635",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-laha",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 69,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ وَلَا تُخْزُونِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "1636",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "till",
        "pcklId": "326",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكَ اللَّعْنَةَ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "till",
        "pcklId": "327",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "Till",
        "pcklId": "328",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْوَقْتِ الْمَعْلُومِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "329",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّا أُرْسِلْنَا إِلَىٰ قَوْمٍ مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَيْهِ",
        "answer": "to him",
        "pcklId": "330",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilayhi",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَضَيْنَا إِلَيْهِ ذَٰلِكَ الْأَمْرَ أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "towards",
        "pcklId": "331",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "answer": "you are ordered",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "tu'marūna",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَلْتَفِتْ مِنْكُمْ أَحَدٌ وَامْضُوا حَيْثُ تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to order, to command",
        "waznTlit": "amara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 77,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْمَرُ",
        "answer": "you are ordered",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "tu'maru",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 94,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْدَعْ بِمَا تُؤْمَرُ وَأَعْرِضْ عَنِ الْمُشْرِكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to order, to command",
        "waznTlit": "amara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 77,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَمْرَ",
        "answer": "the matter",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "l-amra",
        "frequency": 248,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَضَيْنَا إِلَيْهِ ذَٰلِكَ الْأَمْرَ أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَمَلُ",
        "answer": "the hope",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 71,
        "tlit": "l-amalu",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ م ل",
        "waznEnglish": "hope",
        "waznTlit": "hamza mīm lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَبِإِمَامٍ",
        "answer": "(were) on a highway",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "labi-imāmin",
        "frequency": 119,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 79,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْتَقَمْنَا مِنْهُمْ وَإِنَّهُمَا لَبِإِمَامٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِمَام",
        "waznEnglish": "leader, guide, record, highway",
        "waznTlit": "imām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أُمَّةٍ",
        "answer": "nation",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "ummatin",
        "frequency": 119,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا تَسْبِقُ مِنْ أُمَّةٍ أَجَلَهَا وَمَا يَسْتَأْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُمَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "people, nation, community, period of time, religion",
        "waznTlit": "ummat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 64,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "answer": "they believe",
        "pcklId": "311",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "yu'minūna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِهِ وَقَدْ خَلَتْ سُنَّةُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 537,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "secure",
        "pcklId": "593",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "āminīna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " ادْخُلُوهَا بِسَلَامٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "āminīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "secure",
        "pcklId": "594",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "āminīna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 82,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَنْحِتُونَ مِنَ الْجِبَالِ بُيُوتًا آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "āminīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "for the believers",
        "pcklId": "746",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "lil'mu'minīna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 77,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَآيَةً لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 202,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "to the believers",
        "pcklId": "747",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "lil'mu'minīna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَحْزَنْ عَلَيْهِمْ وَاخْفِضْ جَنَاحَكَ لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 202,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانَ",
        "answer": "humankind",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insāna",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 71,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَهْلِكَ",
        "answer": "with your family",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "bi-ahlika",
        "frequency": 127,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 127,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلُ",
        "answer": "(the) people",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "ahlu",
        "frequency": 127,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 67,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَاءَ أَهْلُ الْمَدِينَةِ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 127,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا مِنْ قَبْلِكَ فِي شِيَعِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِهِ وَقَدْ خَلَتْ سُنَّةُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آلَ",
        "answer": "the family",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "āla",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ إِنَّا لَمُنَجُّوهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَال",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "āl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آلَ",
        "answer": "(to the) family",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "āla",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 61,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا جَاءَ آلَ لُوطٍ الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَال",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "āl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَاتُ",
        "answer": "(are) the Verses",
        "pcklId": "160",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyātu",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " الر تِلْكَ آيَاتُ الْكِتَابِ وَقُرْآنٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَآيَاتٍ",
        "answer": "(are) the Signs",
        "pcklId": "161",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "laāyātin",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 75,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَآيَاتٍ لِلْمُتَوَسِّمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَآيَةً",
        "answer": "surely (is) a Sign",
        "pcklId": "162",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "laāyatan",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 77,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَآيَةً لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَاتِنَا",
        "answer": "Our Signs",
        "pcklId": "163",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyātinā",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 81,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ آيَاتِنَا فَكَانُوا عَنْهَا مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بُرُوجًا",
        "answer": "constellations",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 111,
        "tlit": "burūjan",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَعَلْنَا فِي السَّمَاءِ بُرُوجًا وَزَيَّنَّاهَا لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُرُوج",
        "waznEnglish": "display yourselves",
        "waznTlit": "burūj",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُبَشِّرُكَ",
        "answer": "[we] bring glad tidings to you",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "nubashiruka",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَا تَوْجَلْ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَامٍ عَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي",
        "answer": "Do you give me glad tidings",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "abashartumūnī",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي عَلَىٰ أَنْ مَسَّنِيَ الْكِبَرُ فَبِمَ تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "answer": "you give glad tidings",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "tubashirūna",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي عَلَىٰ أَنْ مَسَّنِيَ الْكِبَرُ فَبِمَ تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَشَّرْنَاكَ",
        "answer": "We give you glad tidings",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "basharnāka",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَشَّرْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ فَلَا تَكُنْ مِنَ الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُشِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give glad tidings",
        "waznTlit": "bushira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ",
        "answer": "rejoicing",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "yastabshirūna",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 67,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَاءَ أَهْلُ الْمَدِينَةِ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَبْشِرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to rejoice",
        "waznTlit": "yastabshiru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَشَرًا",
        "answer": "a human being",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "basharan",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِبَشَرٍ",
        "answer": "to a human",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 128,
        "tlit": "libasharin",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَشَر",
        "waznEnglish": "And give good news",
        "waznTlit": "bashar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْصَارُنَا",
        "answer": "our eyes",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "abṣārunā",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَالُوا إِنَّمَا سُكِّرَتْ أَبْصَارُنَا بَلْ نَحْنُ قَوْمٌ مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "answer": "they are raised",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 137,
        "tlit": "yub'ʿathūna",
        "frequency": 67,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعَثَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to raise, to resurrect, to send",
        "waznTlit": "baʿatha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَنَاتِي",
        "answer": "(are) my daughters",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "banātī",
        "frequency": 184,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 71,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ بَنَاتِي إِنْ كُنْتُمْ فَاعِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَنَات",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "banāt",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَابًا",
        "answer": "a gate",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 166,
        "tlit": "bāban",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ فَتَحْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ بَابًا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ فَظَلُّوا فِيهِ يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the gate",
        "waznTlit": "bā wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْوَابٍ",
        "answer": "gates",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 166,
        "tlit": "abwābin",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the gate",
        "waznTlit": "bā wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَابٍ",
        "answer": "gate",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 166,
        "tlit": "bābin",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "the gate",
        "waznTlit": "bā wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 27,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بُيُوتًا",
        "answer": "houses",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 169,
        "tlit": "buyūtan",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 82,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَنْحِتُونَ مِنَ الْجِبَالِ بُيُوتًا آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْت",
        "waznEnglish": "spend (the) night",
        "waznTlit": "bayt",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 65,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "answer": "(is) between them",
        "pcklId": "158",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahumā",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 266,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٍ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "412",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnin",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " الر تِلْكَ آيَاتُ الْكِتَابِ وَقُرْآنٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 119,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "413",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 119,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٍ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "414",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnin",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 79,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْتَقَمْنَا مِنْهُمْ وَإِنَّهُمَا لَبِإِمَامٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 119,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُبِينُ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "415",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "l-mubīnu",
        "frequency": 523,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 89,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقُلْ إِنِّي أَنَا النَّذِيرُ الْمُبِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 119,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَتْبَعَهُ",
        "answer": "then follows him",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "fa-atbaʿahu",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتْبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "atbaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 15,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اتَّبَعَكَ",
        "answer": "follow you",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "ittabaʿaka",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ إِلَّا مَنِ اتَّبَعَكَ مِنَ الْغَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاتَّبِعْ",
        "answer": "and follow",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "wa-ittabiʿ",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَثَانِي",
        "answer": "the oft-repeated",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 210,
        "tlit": "l-mathānī",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 87,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ آتَيْنَاكَ سَبْعًا مِنَ الْمَثَانِي وَالْقُرْآنَ الْعَظِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّثَانِى",
        "waznEnglish": "fold up",
        "waznTlit": "mathānī",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجِبَالِ",
        "answer": "the mountains",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 219,
        "tlit": "l-jibāli",
        "frequency": 41,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 82,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَنْحِتُونَ مِنَ الْجِبَالِ بُيُوتًا آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَبَل",
        "waznEnglish": "hill",
        "waznTlit": "jabal",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 39,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the criminals",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "l-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَسْلُكُهُ فِي قُلُوبِ الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "criminals",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّا أُرْسِلْنَا إِلَىٰ قَوْمٍ مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جُزْءٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a portion",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 243,
        "tlit": "juz'on",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ز أ",
        "waznEnglish": "a portion",
        "waznTlit": "jīm zāy hamza",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We have placed",
        "pcklId": "97",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalnā",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَعَلْنَا فِي السَّمَاءِ بُرُوجًا وَزَيَّنَّاهَا لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We have made",
        "pcklId": "98",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "wajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا لَكُمْ فِيهَا مَعَايِشَ وَمَنْ لَسْتُمْ لَهُ بِرَازِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We made",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalnā",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَا عَالِيَهَا سَافِلَهَا وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَعَلُوا",
        "answer": "have made",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "jaʿalū",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 91,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ جَعَلُوا الْقُرْآنَ عِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَجْعَلُونَ",
        "answer": "set up",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "yajʿalūna",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعُونَ",
        "answer": "together",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿūna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَجَدَ الْمَلَائِكَةُ كُلُّهُمْ أَجْمَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ وَلَأُغْوِيَنَّهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ جَهَنَّمَ لَمَوْعِدُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ إِنَّا لَمُنَجُّوهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 92,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَرَبِّكَ لَنَسْأَلَنَّهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَمِيلَ",
        "answer": "gracious",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 261,
        "tlit": "l-jamīla",
        "frequency": 11,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ السَّاعَةَ لَآتِيَةٌ فَاصْفَحِ الصَّفْحَ الْجَمِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) beauty",
        "waznTlit": "jamīl",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَاحَكَ",
        "answer": "your wing",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 264,
        "tlit": "janāḥaka",
        "frequency": 34,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَحْزَنْ عَلَيْهِمْ وَاخْفِضْ جَنَاحَكَ لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَاح",
        "waznEnglish": "they incline",
        "waznTlit": "janāḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "Gardens",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْجَانَّ",
        "answer": "And the jinn",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "wal-jāna",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجَانَّ خَلَقْنَاهُ مِنْ قَبْلُ مِنْ نَارِ السَّمُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَآنّ",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jānn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "answer": "(are) surely mad",
        "pcklId": "190",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "lamajnūnun",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَ",
        "answer": "came",
        "pcklId": "130",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāa",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 61,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا جَاءَ آلَ لُوطٍ الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جِئْنَاكَ",
        "answer": "we have come to you",
        "pcklId": "131",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "ji'nāka",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 63,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ جِئْنَاكَ بِمَا كَانُوا فِيهِ يَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَاءَ",
        "answer": "And came",
        "pcklId": "132",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "wajāa",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 67,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَاءَ أَهْلُ الْمَدِينَةِ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حِجَارَةً",
        "answer": "stones",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 294,
        "tlit": "ḥijāratan",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَا عَالِيَهَا سَافِلَهَا وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِجَارَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and [the] stones",
        "waznTlit": "ḥijārat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحِجْرِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Rocky Tract",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 294,
        "tlit": "l-ḥij'ri",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 80,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ كَذَّبَ أَصْحَابُ الْحِجْرِ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِجْر",
        "waznEnglish": "and [the] stones",
        "waznTlit": "ḥij'r",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَحْزَنْ",
        "answer": "grieve",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 315,
        "tlit": "taḥzan",
        "frequency": 42,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ وَلَا تَحْزَنْ عَلَيْهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ح ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَحْزُن",
        "waznEnglish": "to grieve",
        "waznTlit": "yaḥzun",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَحْشُرُهُمْ",
        "answer": "will gather them",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 322,
        "tlit": "yaḥshuruhum",
        "frequency": 43,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ يَحْشُرُهُمْ إِنَّهُ حَكِيمٌ عَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَشَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ḥashara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحَفِظْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "And We have protected it",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "waḥafiẓ'nāhā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَفِظْنَاهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ رَجِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَفِظَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to guard, to protect",
        "waznTlit": "ḥafiẓa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَحَافِظُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) surely Guardians",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 339,
        "tlit": "laḥāfiẓūna",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا الذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُ لَحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ف ظ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَٰفِظ",
        "waznEnglish": "(orders) them to guard",
        "waznTlit": "ḥāfiẓ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "with the truth",
        "pcklId": "147",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": 287,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 247,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "in truth",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": 287,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَشَّرْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ فَلَا تَكُنْ مِنَ الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 247,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "with the truth",
        "pcklId": "149",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": 287,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 64,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَتَيْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ وَإِنَّا لَصَادِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 247,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "in truth",
        "pcklId": "150",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": 287,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 247,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَكِيمٌ",
        "answer": "(is) All-Wise",
        "pcklId": "195",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "ḥakīmun",
        "frequency": 210,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ يَحْشُرُهُمْ إِنَّهُ حَكِيمٌ عَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَكِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "will judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥakīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 97,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمَإٍ",
        "answer": "black mud",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 351,
        "tlit": "ḥama-in",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمَإ",
        "waznEnglish": "black mud",
        "waznTlit": "ḥama",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمَإٍ",
        "answer": "black mud",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 351,
        "tlit": "ḥama-in",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمَإ",
        "waznEnglish": "black mud",
        "waznTlit": "ḥama",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَمَإٍ",
        "answer": "black mud",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 351,
        "tlit": "ḥama-in",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح م أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمَإ",
        "waznEnglish": "black mud",
        "waznTlit": "ḥama",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِحَمْدِ",
        "answer": "with the praise",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 352,
        "tlit": "biḥamdi",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 98,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِحَمْدِ رَبِّكَ وَكُنْ مِنَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح م د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمْد",
        "waznEnglish": "they be praised",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 43,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَيْثُ",
        "answer": "where",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 373,
        "tlit": "ḥaythu",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَلْتَفِتْ مِنْكُمْ أَحَدٌ وَامْضُوا حَيْثُ تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيْث",
        "waznEnglish": "wherever",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayth",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُحْيِي",
        "answer": "We give life",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "nuḥ'yī",
        "frequency": 184,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّا لَنَحْنُ نُحْيِي وَنُمِيتُ وَنَحْنُ الْوَارِثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to give life",
        "waznTlit": "aḥyā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 51,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاخْرُجْ",
        "answer": "Then get out",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "fa-ukh'ruj",
        "frequency": 182,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَاخْرُجْ مِنْهَا فَإِنَّكَ رَجِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go out, to come out, to depart, to leave",
        "waznTlit": "kharaja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمُخْرَجِينَ",
        "answer": "will be removed",
        "pcklId": "177",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "bimukh'rajīna",
        "frequency": 182,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُمْ فِيهَا نَصَبٌ وَمَا هُمْ مِنْهَا بِمُخْرَجِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْرَج",
        "waznEnglish": "so comes out",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'raj",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَزَائِنُهُ",
        "answer": "(are) its treasures",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 403,
        "tlit": "khazāinuhu",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَزَآئِن",
        "waznEnglish": "(are the) treasures",
        "waznTlit": "khazāin",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِخَازِنِينَ",
        "answer": "(are) retainers",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 403,
        "tlit": "bikhāzinīna",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ وَمَا أَنْتُمْ لَهُ بِخَازِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَٰزِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(are the) treasures",
        "waznTlit": "khāzinīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُخْزُونِ",
        "answer": "disgrace me",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 404,
        "tlit": "tukh'zūni",
        "frequency": 26,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 69,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ وَلَا تُخْزُونِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْزَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disgrace",
        "waznTlit": "akhzay",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَطْبُكُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) your business",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 418,
        "tlit": "khaṭbukum",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 57,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَمَا خَطْبُكُمْ أَيُّهَا الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ط ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَطْب",
        "waznEnglish": "address Me",
        "waznTlit": "khaṭb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاخْفِضْ",
        "answer": "And lower",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 423,
        "tlit": "wa-ikh'fiḍ",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَحْزَنْ عَلَيْهِمْ وَاخْفِضْ جَنَاحَكَ لِلْمُؤْمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ف ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱخْفِضْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to lower",
        "waznTlit": "ikh'fiḍ",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "answer": "the ones who are sincere",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 427,
        "tlit": "l-mukh'laṣīna",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَكَ مِنْهُمُ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ص",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُخْلَص",
        "waznEnglish": "they secluded themselves",
        "waznTlit": "mukh'laṣ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We created",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnā",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We created it",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnāhu",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجَانَّ خَلَقْنَاهُ مِنْ قَبْلُ مِنْ نَارِ السَّمُومِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْتَهُ",
        "answer": "whom You created",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqtahu",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We created",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnā",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخَلَّاقُ",
        "answer": "(is) the Creator",
        "pcklId": "184",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "l-khalāqu",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 86,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ الْخَلَّاقُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَّٰق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khallāq",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَالِقٌ",
        "answer": "(will) create",
        "pcklId": "248",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khāliqun",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَٰلِق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khāliq",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَتْ",
        "answer": "have passed",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 433,
        "tlit": "khalat",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِهِ وَقَدْ خَلَتْ سُنَّةُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to pass away",
        "waznTlit": "khalā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 25,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "دَابِرَ",
        "answer": "(the) root",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "dābira",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَضَيْنَا إِلَيْهِ ذَٰلِكَ الْأَمْرَ أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَابِر",
        "waznEnglish": "disposing",
        "waznTlit": "dābir",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their backs",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 455,
        "tlit": "adbārahum",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "د ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُبُر",
        "waznEnglish": "disposing",
        "waznTlit": "dubur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ادْخُلُوهَا",
        "answer": "Enter it",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 461,
        "tlit": "ud'khulūhā",
        "frequency": 126,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " ادْخُلُوهَا بِسَلَامٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَخَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to enter",
        "waznTlit": "dakhala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "دَخَلُوا",
        "answer": "they entered",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 461,
        "tlit": "dakhalū",
        "frequency": 126,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَخَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to enter",
        "waznTlit": "dakhala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدِّينِ",
        "answer": "(of) [the] Judgment",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 498,
        "tlit": "l-dīni",
        "frequency": 101,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكَ اللَّعْنَةَ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "د ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they acknowledge",
        "waznTlit": "dīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 92,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرُ",
        "answer": "the Reminder",
        "pcklId": "206",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'ru",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرَ",
        "answer": "the Reminder",
        "pcklId": "207",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'ra",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا الذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُ لَحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "357",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ يَحْشُرُهُمْ إِنَّهُ حَكِيمٌ عَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord said",
        "pcklId": "358",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "O my Lord",
        "pcklId": "359",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "My Lord",
        "pcklId": "360",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "361",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "362",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 86,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ الْخَلَّاقُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَوَرَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "So by your Lord",
        "pcklId": "363",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "fawarabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 92,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَرَبِّكَ لَنَسْأَلَنَّهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "364",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 98,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِحَمْدِ رَبِّكَ وَكُنْ مِنَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "365",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 99,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاعْبُدْ رَبَّكَ حَتَّىٰ يَأْتِيَكَ الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَجِيمٍ",
        "answer": "accursed",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 539,
        "tlit": "rajīmin",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَفِظْنَاهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ رَجِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَجِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "surely we would have stoned you",
        "waznTlit": "rajīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَجِيمٌ",
        "answer": "(are) expelled",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 539,
        "tlit": "rajīmun",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَاخْرُجْ مِنْهَا فَإِنَّكَ رَجِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَجِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "surely we would have stoned you",
        "waznTlit": "rajīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَحْمَةِ",
        "answer": "(the) Mercy",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "raḥmati",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَحْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 114,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحِيمُ",
        "answer": "the Most Merciful",
        "pcklId": "270",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥīmu",
        "frequency": 339,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " نَبِّئْ عِبَادِي أَنِّي أَنَا الْغَفُورُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 116,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِرَازِقِينَ",
        "answer": "providers",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 552,
        "tlit": "birāziqīna",
        "frequency": 123,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا لَكُمْ فِيهَا مَعَايِشَ وَمَنْ لَسْتُمْ لَهُ بِرَازِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ز ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّٰزِقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We have provided them",
        "waznTlit": "rāziqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We (had) sent",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "arsalnā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا مِنْ قَبْلِكَ فِي شِيَعِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَرْسَلْنَا",
        "answer": "And We have sent",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "wa-arsalnā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أُرْسِلْنَا",
        "answer": "[we] have been sent",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "ur'sil'nā",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّا أُرْسِلْنَا إِلَىٰ قَوْمٍ مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 130,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَسُولٍ",
        "answer": "Messenger",
        "pcklId": "304",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "rasūlin",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَأْتِيهِمْ مِنْ رَسُولٍ إِلَّا كَانُوا بِهِ يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَسُول",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "rasūl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 332,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "answer": "O messengers",
        "pcklId": "484",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salūna",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 57,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَمَا خَطْبُكُمْ أَيُّهَا الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "answer": "the messengers",
        "pcklId": "485",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salūna",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 61,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا جَاءَ آلَ لُوطٍ الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "answer": "the Messengers",
        "pcklId": "486",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "l-mur'salīna",
        "frequency": 513,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 80,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ كَذَّبَ أَصْحَابُ الْحِجْرِ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْسَل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sal",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَوَاسِيَ",
        "answer": "firm mountains",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 556,
        "tlit": "rawāsiya",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ مَدَدْنَاهَا وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَوَٰسِى",
        "waznEnglish": "He made them firm",
        "waznTlit": "rawāsī",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رُوحِي",
        "answer": "My spirit",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "rūḥī",
        "frequency": 57,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رُوح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rūḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الرِّيَاحَ",
        "answer": "the winds",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 599,
        "tlit": "l-riyāḥa",
        "frequency": 57,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ",
        "rootWord": "ر و ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رِيح",
        "waznEnglish": "you bring them in",
        "waznTlit": "rīḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزْوَاجًا",
        "answer": "(to) categories",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "azwājan",
        "frequency": 81,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَزَيَّنَّاهَا",
        "answer": "and We have beautified it",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 646,
        "tlit": "wazayyannāhā",
        "frequency": 46,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَعَلْنَا فِي السَّمَاءِ بُرُوجًا وَزَيَّنَّاهَا لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَيَّنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make fair",
        "waznTlit": "zayyana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ",
        "answer": "surely, I will make (evil) fair-seeming",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 646,
        "tlit": "la-uzayyinanna",
        "frequency": 46,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَيَّنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make fair",
        "waznTlit": "zayyana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَنَسْأَلَنَّهُمْ",
        "answer": "surely We will question them",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "lanasalannahum",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 92,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَوَرَبِّكَ لَنَسْأَلَنَّهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 106,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَبِّحْ",
        "answer": "So glorify",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "fasabbiḥ",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 98,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِحَمْدِ رَبِّكَ وَكُنْ مِنَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to glorify, to praise",
        "waznTlit": "sabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبْعًا",
        "answer": "seven",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 653,
        "tlit": "sabʿan",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 87,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ آتَيْنَاكَ سَبْعًا مِنَ الْمَثَانِي وَالْقُرْآنَ الْعَظِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبْع",
        "waznEnglish": "seven",
        "waznTlit": "sabʿ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبْعَةُ",
        "answer": "(are) seven",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 653,
        "tlit": "sabʿatu",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبْعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "seven",
        "waznTlit": "sabʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَسْبِقُ",
        "answer": "(can) advance",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 655,
        "tlit": "tasbiqu",
        "frequency": 37,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا تَسْبِقُ مِنْ أُمَّةٍ أَجَلَهَا وَمَا يَسْتَأْخِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to precede",
        "waznTlit": "sabaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَبِسَبِيلٍ",
        "answer": "(is) on a road",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 656,
        "tlit": "labisabīlin",
        "frequency": 176,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 76,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهَا لَبِسَبِيلٍ مُقِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ب ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the way",
        "waznTlit": "sīn bā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَجَدَ",
        "answer": "So prostrated",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "fasajada",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَجَدَ الْمَلَائِكَةُ كُلُّهُمْ أَجْمَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِأَسْجُدَ",
        "answer": "(one) to prostrate",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "li-asjuda",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَاجِدِينَ",
        "answer": "prostrating",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "sājidīna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاجِد",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sājid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "answer": "those who prostrated",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "l-sājidīna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا إِبْلِيسَ أَبَىٰ أَنْ يَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاجِد",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sājid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "answer": "those who prostrated",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "l-sājidīna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا إِبْلِيسُ مَا لَكَ أَلَّا تَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاجِد",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sājid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "answer": "those who prostrate",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "l-sājidīna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 98,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِحَمْدِ رَبِّكَ وَكُنْ مِنَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاجِد",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sājid",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سِجِّيلٍ",
        "answer": "baked clay",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 661,
        "tlit": "sijjīlin",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَا عَالِيَهَا سَافِلَهَا وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِجِّيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) a scroll",
        "waznTlit": "sijjīl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "answer": "bewitched",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 666,
        "tlit": "masḥūrūna",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ نَحْنُ قَوْمٌ مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّسْحُور",
        "waznEnglish": "they bewitched",
        "waznTlit": "masḥūr",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُرُرٍ",
        "answer": "thrones",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 681,
        "tlit": "sururin",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُرُر",
        "waznEnglish": "pleasing",
        "waznTlit": "surur",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اسْتَرَقَ",
        "answer": "steals",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 684,
        "tlit": "is'taraqa",
        "frequency": 9,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَرَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to steal",
        "waznTlit": "is'taraqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَسْرِ",
        "answer": "So travel",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 686,
        "tlit": "fa-asri",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to travel, to take",
        "waznTlit": "asrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَافِلَهَا",
        "answer": "its lowest",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 698,
        "tlit": "sāfilahā",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَا عَالِيَهَا سَافِلَهَا وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ف ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَافِل",
        "waznEnglish": "below",
        "waznTlit": "sāfil",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ",
        "answer": "and We gave it to you to drink",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 704,
        "tlit": "fa-asqaynākumūhu",
        "frequency": 25,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ",
        "rootWord": "س ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْقَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give drink",
        "waznTlit": "asqay",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُكِّرَتْ",
        "answer": "have been dazzled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 707,
        "tlit": "sukkirat",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَالُوا إِنَّمَا سُكِّرَتْ أَبْصَارُنَا بَلْ نَحْنُ قَوْمٌ مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُكِّرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dazzle",
        "waznTlit": "sukkirat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَكْرَتِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their intoxication",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 707,
        "tlit": "sakratihim",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 72,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَعَمْرُكَ إِنَّهُمْ لَفِي سَكْرَتِهِمْ يَعْمَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَكْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "have been dazzled",
        "waznTlit": "sakrat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُلْطَانٌ",
        "answer": "any authority",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 713,
        "tlit": "sul'ṭānun",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ إِلَّا مَنِ اتَّبَعَكَ مِنَ الْغَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُلْطَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "surely He (would have) given them power",
        "waznTlit": "sul'ṭān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَسْلُكُهُ",
        "answer": "We let it enter",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 716,
        "tlit": "naslukuhu",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَسْلُكُهُ فِي قُلُوبِ الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ل ك",
        "waznEnglish": "to insert, to make enter",
        "waznTlit": "sīn lām kāf",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِسَلَامٍ",
        "answer": "in peace",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "bisalāmin",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ادْخُلُوهَا بِسَلَامٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلَامًا",
        "answer": "Peace",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "salāman",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَلَٰم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "salām",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "answer": "Muslims",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "mus'limīna",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " رُبَمَا يَوَدُّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَوْ كَانُوا مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْلِم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "mus'lim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 39,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمْعَ",
        "answer": "the hearing",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "l-samʿa",
        "frequency": 185,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمْع",
        "waznEnglish": "(who used to) hear",
        "waznTlit": "samʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 22,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمُومِ",
        "answer": "scorching",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 724,
        "tlit": "l-samūmi",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجَانَّ خَلَقْنَاهُ مِنْ قَبْلُ مِنْ نَارِ السَّمُومِ",
        "rootWord": "س م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) eye",
        "waznTlit": "samūm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءِ",
        "answer": "the heaven",
        "pcklId": "141",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāi",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ فَتَحْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ بَابًا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ فَظَلُّوا فِيهِ يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءِ",
        "answer": "the heavens",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāi",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَعَلْنَا فِي السَّمَاءِ بُرُوجًا وَزَيَّنَّاهَا لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءِ",
        "answer": "the sky",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāi",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "the heavens",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُنَّةُ",
        "answer": "the way(s)",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 730,
        "tlit": "sunnatu",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِهِ وَقَدْ خَلَتْ سُنَّةُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "and the tooth",
        "waznTlit": "sunnat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "altered",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 730,
        "tlit": "masnūnin",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّسْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and the tooth",
        "waznTlit": "masnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "altered",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 730,
        "tlit": "masnūnin",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّسْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and the tooth",
        "waznTlit": "masnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "altered",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 730,
        "tlit": "masnūnin",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّسْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and the tooth",
        "waznTlit": "masnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاعَةَ",
        "answer": "the Hour",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 742,
        "tlit": "l-sāʿata",
        "frequency": 49,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ السَّاعَةَ لَآتِيَةٌ فَاصْفَحِ الصَّفْحَ الْجَمِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "س و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the Hour",
        "waznTlit": "sāʿat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَوَّيْتُهُ",
        "answer": "I have fashioned him",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "sawwaytuhu",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُشْرِقِينَ",
        "answer": "at sunrise",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 770,
        "tlit": "mush'riqīna",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 73,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُشْرِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّشْرِقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will) shine",
        "waznTlit": "mush'riqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُشْرِكِينَ",
        "answer": "the polytheists",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 771,
        "tlit": "l-mush'rikīna",
        "frequency": 168,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 94,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْدَعْ بِمَا تُؤْمَرُ وَأَعْرِضْ عَنِ الْمُشْرِكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُشْرِك",
        "waznEnglish": "and be a partner",
        "waznTlit": "mush'rik",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْطَانٍ",
        "answer": "devil",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 776,
        "tlit": "shayṭānin",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَفِظْنَاهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ رَجِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ط ن",
        "waznEnglish": "the Shaitaan",
        "waznTlit": "shīn ṭā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شِهَابٌ",
        "answer": "a burning flame",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 800,
        "tlit": "shihābun",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنِ اسْتَرَقَ السَّمْعَ فَأَتْبَعَهُ شِهَابٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ش ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِهَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "a burning flame",
        "waznTlit": "shihāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "359",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ مَوْزُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْءٍ",
        "answer": "thing",
        "pcklId": "360",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayin",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شِيَعِ",
        "answer": "the sects",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 814,
        "tlit": "shiyaʿi",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا مِنْ قَبْلِكَ فِي شِيَعِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِيعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) spread",
        "waznTlit": "shīʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "answer": "(by) early morning",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "muṣ'biḥīna",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصْبِحِين",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "muṣ'biḥīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "answer": "(at) early morning",
        "pcklId": "41",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "muṣ'biḥīna",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 83,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصْبِحِين",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "muṣ'biḥīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 78,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ كَانَ أَصْحَابُ الْأَيْكَةِ لَظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابُ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥābu",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 80,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ كَذَّبَ أَصْحَابُ الْحِجْرِ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صُدُورِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their breasts",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 827,
        "tlit": "ṣudūrihim",
        "frequency": 46,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدْر",
        "waznEnglish": "will proceed",
        "waznTlit": "ṣadr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَدْرُكَ",
        "answer": "your breast",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 827,
        "tlit": "ṣadruka",
        "frequency": 46,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 97,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَعْلَمُ أَنَّكَ يَضِيقُ صَدْرُكَ بِمَا يَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدْر",
        "waznEnglish": "will proceed",
        "waznTlit": "ṣadr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاصْدَعْ",
        "answer": "So proclaim",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 828,
        "tlit": "fa-iṣ'daʿ",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 94,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْدَعْ بِمَا تُؤْمَرُ وَأَعْرِضْ عَنِ الْمُشْرِكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱصْدَعْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to proclaim",
        "waznTlit": "iṣ'daʿ",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّادِقِينَ",
        "answer": "the truthful",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "l-ṣādiqīna",
        "frequency": 155,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ مَا تَأْتِينَا بِالْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنْ كُنْتَ مِنَ الصَّادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 59,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَصَادِقُونَ",
        "answer": "surely (are) truthful",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "laṣādiqūna",
        "frequency": 155,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 64,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَتَيْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ وَإِنَّا لَصَادِقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 59,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صِرَاطٌ",
        "answer": "(is) the way",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 836,
        "tlit": "ṣirāṭun",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰذَا صِرَاطٌ عَلَيَّ مُسْتَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ر ط",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) the path",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād rā ṭā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاصْفَحِ",
        "answer": "So overlook",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 845,
        "tlit": "fa-iṣ'faḥi",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ السَّاعَةَ لَآتِيَةٌ فَاصْفَحِ الصَّفْحَ الْجَمِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصْفَحُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to overlook",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣfaḥu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّفْحَ",
        "answer": "(with) forgiveness",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 845,
        "tlit": "l-ṣafḥa",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 85,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ السَّاعَةَ لَآتِيَةٌ فَاصْفَحِ الصَّفْحَ الْجَمِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ف ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَفْح",
        "waznEnglish": "and overlook",
        "waznTlit": "ṣafḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلْصَالٍ",
        "answer": "sounding clay",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 856,
        "tlit": "ṣalṣālin",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ خَلَقْنَا الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ل ص ل",
        "waznEnglish": "sounding clay",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād lām ṣād lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلْصَالٍ",
        "answer": "clay",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 856,
        "tlit": "ṣalṣālin",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ل ص ل",
        "waznEnglish": "sounding clay",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād lām ṣād lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلْصَالٍ",
        "answer": "clay",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 856,
        "tlit": "ṣalṣālin",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ل ص ل",
        "waznEnglish": "sounding clay",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād lām ṣād lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّيْحَةُ",
        "answer": "the awful cry",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 873,
        "tlit": "l-ṣayḥatu",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 73,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُشْرِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ي ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ي ح",
        "waznEnglish": "the thunderous blast",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād yā ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّيْحَةُ",
        "answer": "the awful cry",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 873,
        "tlit": "l-ṣayḥatu",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 83,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَخَذَتْهُمُ الصَّيْحَةُ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ي ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ص ي ح",
        "waznEnglish": "the thunderous blast",
        "waznTlit": "ṣād yā ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الضَّالُّونَ",
        "answer": "those who are astray",
        "pcklId": "176",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "l-ḍālūna",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَيْفِ",
        "answer": "(the) guests",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 901,
        "tlit": "ḍayfi",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ عَنْ ضَيْفِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَيْف",
        "waznEnglish": "offer them hospitality",
        "waznTlit": "ḍayf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَيْفِي",
        "answer": "(are) my guests",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 901,
        "tlit": "ḍayfī",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 68,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ ضَيْفِي فَلَا تَفْضَحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ض ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَيْف",
        "waznEnglish": "offer them hospitality",
        "waznTlit": "ḍayf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَضِيقُ",
        "answer": "(is) straitened",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 902,
        "tlit": "yaḍīqu",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 97,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَعْلَمُ أَنَّكَ يَضِيقُ صَدْرُكَ بِمَا يَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ي ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَاقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to straiten",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَظَلُّوا",
        "answer": "and they were to continue",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 941,
        "tlit": "faẓallū",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ فَتَحْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ بَابًا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ فَظَلُّوا فِيهِ يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to continue, to remain",
        "waznTlit": "ẓalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَظَالِمِينَ",
        "answer": "surely wrongdoers",
        "pcklId": "227",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "laẓālimīna",
        "frequency": 315,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 78,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ كَانَ أَصْحَابُ الْأَيْكَةِ لَظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَالِم",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] have wronged",
        "waznTlit": "ẓālim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 129,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاعْبُدْ",
        "answer": "And worship",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "wa-uʿ'bud",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 99,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاعْبُدْ رَبَّكَ حَتَّىٰ يَأْتِيَكَ الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 122,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَكَ",
        "answer": "Your slaves",
        "pcklId": "161",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādaka",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا عِبَادَكَ مِنْهُمُ الْمُخْلَصِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 131,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِي",
        "answer": "My slaves",
        "pcklId": "162",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādī",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 131,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادِي",
        "answer": "My slaves",
        "pcklId": "163",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibādī",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " نَبِّئْ عِبَادِي أَنِّي أَنَا الْغَفُورُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 131,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِي",
        "answer": "My punishment",
        "pcklId": "163",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābī",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ عَذَابِي هُوَ الْعَذَابُ الْأَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابُ",
        "answer": "(is) the punishment",
        "pcklId": "164",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābu",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ عَذَابِي هُوَ الْعَذَابُ الْأَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "answer": "(to) ascend",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 971,
        "tlit": "yaʿrujūna",
        "frequency": 9,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ فَتَحْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ بَابًا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ فَظَلُّوا فِيهِ يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَعْرُجُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ascend",
        "waznTlit": "yaʿruju",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَعْرِضْ",
        "answer": "and turn away",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 975,
        "tlit": "wa-aʿriḍ",
        "frequency": 79,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 94,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْدَعْ بِمَا تُؤْمَرُ وَأَعْرِضْ عَنِ الْمُشْرِكِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْرَضَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away",
        "waznTlit": "aʿraḍa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 32,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "answer": "turning away",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 975,
        "tlit": "muʿ'riḍīna",
        "frequency": 79,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 81,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ آيَاتِنَا فَكَانُوا عَنْهَا مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّعْرِضُون",
        "waznEnglish": "He displayed them",
        "waznTlit": "muʿ'riḍūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 19,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِضِينَ",
        "answer": "(in) parts",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1001,
        "tlit": "ʿiḍīna",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 91,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ جَعَلُوا الْقُرْآنَ عِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ض و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع ض و",
        "waznEnglish": "(in) parts",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn ḍād wāw",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمَ",
        "answer": "Great",
        "pcklId": "56",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīma",
        "frequency": 128,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 87,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ آتَيْنَاكَ سَبْعًا مِنَ الْمَثَانِي وَالْقُرْآنَ الْعَظِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 120,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "they will come to know",
        "pcklId": "186",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِمْنَا",
        "answer": "We know",
        "pcklId": "187",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalim'nā",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْنَا الْمُسْتَقْدِمِينَ مِنْكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِمْنَا",
        "answer": "We know",
        "pcklId": "188",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalim'nā",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْنَا الْمُسْتَأْخِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "they will come to know",
        "pcklId": "189",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 96,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْعَلُونَ مَعَ اللَّهِ إِلَٰهًا آخَرَ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "We know",
        "pcklId": "190",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "naʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 97,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَعْلَمُ أَنَّكَ يَضِيقُ صَدْرُكَ بِمَا يَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "the world",
        "pcklId": "504",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 70,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا أَوَلَمْ نَنْهَكَ عَنِ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِيمٌ",
        "answer": "All-Knowing",
        "pcklId": "711",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalīmun",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ يَحْشُرُهُمْ إِنَّهُ حَكِيمٌ عَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 163,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلِيمٍ",
        "answer": "learned",
        "pcklId": "712",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿalīmin",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَا تَوْجَلْ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَامٍ عَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 163,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَلِيمُ",
        "answer": "the All-Knower",
        "pcklId": "713",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿalīmu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 86,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ الْخَلَّاقُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 163,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٌ",
        "answer": "known",
        "pcklId": "842",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmun",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَهْلَكْنَا مِنْ قَرْيَةٍ إِلَّا وَلَهَا كِتَابٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعْلُومٍ",
        "answer": "known",
        "pcklId": "843",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "maʿlūmin",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَعْلُومِ",
        "answer": "well-known",
        "pcklId": "844",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-maʿlūmi",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْوَقْتِ الْمَعْلُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّعْلُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "maʿlūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَالِيَهَا",
        "answer": "its highest (part)",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "ʿāliyahā",
        "frequency": 70,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلْنَا عَالِيَهَا سَافِلَهَا وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَالِي",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālī",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَعَمْرُكَ",
        "answer": "By your life",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1020,
        "tlit": "laʿamruka",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 72,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " لَعَمْرُكَ إِنَّهُمْ لَفِي سَكْرَتِهِمْ يَعْمَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they maintain",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "answer": "do",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "yaʿmalūna",
        "frequency": 360,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 93,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " عَمَّا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 276,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْمَهُونَ",
        "answer": "wandering blindly",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1024,
        "tlit": "yaʿmahūna",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 72,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " لَعَمْرُكَ إِنَّهُمْ لَفِي سَكْرَتِهِمْ يَعْمَهُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع م ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع م ه",
        "waznEnglish": "to wander blindly",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn mīm hā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَنَا",
        "answer": "with Us",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindanā",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعَايِشَ",
        "answer": "means of living",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1044,
        "tlit": "maʿāyisha",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا لَكُمْ فِيهَا مَعَايِشَ وَمَنْ لَسْتُمْ لَهُ بِرَازِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَعَٰيِش",
        "waznEnglish": "a life",
        "waznTlit": "maʿāyish",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعُيُونٍ",
        "answer": "and water springs",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "waʿuyūnin",
        "frequency": 65,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَيْنَيْكَ",
        "answer": "your eyes",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "ʿaynayka",
        "frequency": 65,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "answer": "those who remain behind",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1048,
        "tlit": "l-ghābirīna",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا امْرَأَتَهُ قَدَّرْنَا إِنَّهَا لَمِنَ الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَٰبِرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) dust",
        "waznTlit": "ghābirīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَفُورُ",
        "answer": "the Oft-Forgiving",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 1071,
        "tlit": "l-ghafūru",
        "frequency": 234,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " نَبِّئْ عِبَادِي أَنِّي أَنَا الْغَفُورُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "غ ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَفُور",
        "waznEnglish": "We will forgive",
        "waznTlit": "ghafūr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 91,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غِلٍّ",
        "answer": "rancor",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1077,
        "tlit": "ghillin",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غِلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he defrauds",
        "waznTlit": "ghill",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِغُلَامٍ",
        "answer": "of a boy",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1078,
        "tlit": "bighulāmin",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَا تَوْجَلْ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَامٍ عَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غ ل م",
        "waznEnglish": "a son",
        "waznTlit": "ghayn lām mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "availed",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "aghnā",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 84,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا أَغْنَىٰ عَنْهُمْ مَا كَانُوا يَكْسِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to prosper",
        "waznTlit": "aghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 15,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَغْوَيْتَنِي",
        "answer": "You misled me",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "aghwaytanī",
        "frequency": 22,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْوَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to mislead, to lead astray",
        "waznTlit": "aghway",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلَأُغْوِيَنَّهُمْ",
        "answer": "and I will mislead them",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "wala-ugh'wiyannahum",
        "frequency": 22,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ وَلَأُغْوِيَنَّهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْوَيْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to mislead, to lead astray",
        "waznTlit": "aghway",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَاوِينَ",
        "answer": "the ones who go astray",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "l-ghāwīna",
        "frequency": 22,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ إِلَّا مَنِ اتَّبَعَكَ مِنَ الْغَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَٰوِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and erred",
        "waznTlit": "ghāwīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَحْنَا",
        "answer": "We opened",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1101,
        "tlit": "fataḥnā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ فَتَحْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ بَابًا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ فَظَلُّوا فِيهِ يَعْرُجُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَتَحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to open, to give victory",
        "waznTlit": "fataḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَفْضَحُونِ",
        "answer": "shame me",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1137,
        "tlit": "tafḍaḥūni",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 68,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ ضَيْفِي فَلَا تَفْضَحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ض ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف ض ح",
        "waznEnglish": "to shame",
        "waznTlit": "fā ḍād ḥā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاعِلِينَ",
        "answer": "doers",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "fāʿilīna",
        "frequency": 108,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 71,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ بَنَاتِي إِنْ كُنْتُمْ فَاعِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَاعِل",
        "waznEnglish": "you do",
        "waznTlit": "fāʿil",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلِكَ",
        "answer": "before you",
        "pcklId": "123",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablika",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ أَرْسَلْنَا مِنْ قَبْلِكَ فِي شِيَعِ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 242,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلُ",
        "answer": "before",
        "pcklId": "124",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablu",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجَانَّ خَلَقْنَاهُ مِنْ قَبْلُ مِنْ نَارِ السَّمُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 242,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "answer": "facing each other",
        "pcklId": "289",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "mutaqābilīna",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّتَقَٰبِلِين",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "mutaqābilīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VI)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّرْنَا",
        "answer": "We have decreed",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qaddarnā",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا امْرَأَتَهُ قَدَّرْنَا إِنَّهَا لَمِنَ الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِقَدَرٍ",
        "answer": "in a measure",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "biqadarin",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qadar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَقْدِمِينَ",
        "answer": "the preceding ones",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 1183,
        "tlit": "l-mus'taqdimīna",
        "frequency": 48,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ عَلِمْنَا الْمُسْتَقْدِمِينَ مِنْكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ق د م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَقْدِمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "He will precede",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqdimīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقُرْآنٍ",
        "answer": "and Quran",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "waqur'ānin",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " الر تِلْكَ آيَاتُ الْكِتَابِ وَقُرْآنٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "and the Quran",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "wal-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 87,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ آتَيْنَاكَ سَبْعًا مِنَ الْمَثَانِي وَالْقُرْآنَ الْعَظِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُرْآنَ",
        "answer": "the Quran",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "l-qur'āna",
        "frequency": 88,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 91,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ جَعَلُوا الْقُرْآنَ عِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرْيَةٍ",
        "answer": "town",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1196,
        "tlit": "qaryatin",
        "frequency": 57,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَهْلَكْنَا مِنْ قَرْيَةٍ إِلَّا وَلَهَا كِتَابٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ر ي",
        "waznEnglish": "town",
        "waznTlit": "qāf rā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 57,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقْسُومٌ",
        "answer": "assigned",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "maqsūmun",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّقْسُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "distribute",
        "waznTlit": "maqsūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُقْتَسِمِينَ",
        "answer": "those who divided",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "l-muq'tasimīna",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 90,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَمَا أَنْزَلْنَا عَلَى الْمُقْتَسِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُقْتَسِمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "distribute",
        "waznTlit": "muq'tasimīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَضَيْنَا",
        "answer": "And We conveyed",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1212,
        "tlit": "waqaḍaynā",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَضَيْنَا إِلَيْهِ ذَٰلِكَ الْأَمْرَ أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ض ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَضَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to decree, to decide, to judge",
        "waznTlit": "qaḍā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 59,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِقِطْعٍ",
        "answer": "in a portion",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1215,
        "tlit": "biqiṭ'ʿin",
        "frequency": 36,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ق ط ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِطْع",
        "waznEnglish": "and [they] cut",
        "waznTlit": "qiṭ'ʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقْطُوعٌ",
        "answer": "would be cut off",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1215,
        "tlit": "maqṭūʿun",
        "frequency": 36,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 66,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَضَيْنَا إِلَيْهِ ذَٰلِكَ الْأَمْرَ أَنَّ دَابِرَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ مَقْطُوعٌ مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ط ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقْطُوع",
        "waznEnglish": "and [they] cut",
        "waznTlit": "maqṭūʿ",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قُلُوبِ",
        "answer": "(the) hearts",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 1222,
        "tlit": "qulūbi",
        "frequency": 168,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ نَسْلُكُهُ فِي قُلُوبِ الْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلْب",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be returned",
        "waznTlit": "qalb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 132,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقْنَطُ",
        "answer": "despairs",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1235,
        "tlit": "yaqnaṭu",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ن ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَنَطُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to despair",
        "waznTlit": "qanaṭu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "answer": "the despairing",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1235,
        "tlit": "l-qāniṭīna",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَشَّرْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ فَلَا تَكُنْ مِنَ الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ن ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَٰنِطِين",
        "waznEnglish": "despairs",
        "waznTlit": "qāniṭīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "And they say",
        "pcklId": "736",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "They would surely say",
        "pcklId": "737",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "laqālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَالُوا إِنَّمَا سُكِّرَتْ أَبْصَارُنَا بَلْ نَحْنُ قَوْمٌ مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "your Lord said",
        "pcklId": "738",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "739",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا إِبْلِيسُ مَا لَكَ أَلَّا تَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "740",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "741",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَاخْرُجْ مِنْهَا فَإِنَّكَ رَجِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "742",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "743",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَإِنَّكَ مِنَ الْمُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "744",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ بِمَا أَغْوَيْتَنِي لَأُزَيِّنَنَّ لَهُمْ فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "745",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰذَا صِرَاطٌ عَلَيَّ مُسْتَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "and said",
        "pcklId": "746",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "faqālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "747",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "748",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَا تَوْجَلْ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَامٍ عَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "749",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي عَلَىٰ أَنْ مَسَّنِيَ الْكِبَرُ فَبِمَ تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "750",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَشَّرْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ فَلَا تَكُنْ مِنَ الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "751",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ وَمَنْ يَقْنَطُ مِنْ رَحْمَةِ رَبِّهِ إِلَّا الضَّالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "752",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 57,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَمَا خَطْبُكُمْ أَيُّهَا الْمُرْسَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "753",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّا أُرْسِلْنَا إِلَىٰ قَوْمٍ مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "754",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّكُمْ قَوْمٌ مُنْكَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "755",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 63,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ جِئْنَاكَ بِمَا كَانُوا فِيهِ يَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "756",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 68,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ ضَيْفِي فَلَا تَفْضَحُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "757",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 70,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا أَوَلَمْ نَنْهَكَ عَنِ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "He said",
        "pcklId": "758",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 71,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ بَنَاتِي إِنْ كُنْتُمْ فَاعِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقُلْ",
        "answer": "And say",
        "pcklId": "759",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqul",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 89,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقُلْ إِنِّي أَنَا النَّذِيرُ الْمُبِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "they say",
        "pcklId": "760",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlūna",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 97,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَعْلَمُ أَنَّكَ يَضِيقُ صَدْرُكَ بِمَا يَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمٌ",
        "answer": "(are) a people",
        "pcklId": "302",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmun",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَالُوا إِنَّمَا سُكِّرَتْ أَبْصَارُنَا بَلْ نَحْنُ قَوْمٌ مَسْحُورُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمٍ",
        "answer": "a people ",
        "pcklId": "303",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmin",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا إِنَّا أُرْسِلْنَا إِلَىٰ قَوْمٍ مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمٌ",
        "answer": "(are) a people",
        "pcklId": "304",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmun",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّكُمْ قَوْمٌ مُنْكَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُقِيمٍ",
        "answer": "established",
        "pcklId": "614",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "muqīmin",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 76,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّهَا لَبِسَبِيلٍ مُقِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّقِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "muqīm",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُسْتَقِيمٌ",
        "answer": "straight",
        "pcklId": "627",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "mus'taqīmun",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰذَا صِرَاطٌ عَلَيَّ مُسْتَقِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّسْتَقِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqīm",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكِبَرُ",
        "answer": "old age",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kibaru",
        "frequency": 161,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي عَلَىٰ أَنْ مَسَّنِيَ الْكِبَرُ فَبِمَ تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِبَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kibar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكِتَابِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Book",
        "pcklId": "185",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "l-kitābi",
        "frequency": 319,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الر تِلْكَ آيَاتُ الْكِتَابِ وَقُرْآنٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 260,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كِتَابٌ",
        "answer": "a decree",
        "pcklId": "186",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "kitābun",
        "frequency": 319,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَهْلَكْنَا مِنْ قَرْيَةٍ إِلَّا وَلَهَا كِتَابٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 260,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "denied",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhaba",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 80,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ كَذَّبَ أَصْحَابُ الْحِجْرِ الْمُرْسَلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكْسِبُونَ",
        "answer": "earn",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1269,
        "tlit": "yaksibūna",
        "frequency": 67,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 84,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا أَغْنَىٰ عَنْهُمْ مَا كَانُوا يَكْسِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَسَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to earn",
        "waznTlit": "kasaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 62,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَفَرُوا",
        "answer": "disbelieved",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "kafarū",
        "frequency": 525,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " رُبَمَا يَوَدُّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَوْ كَانُوا مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 289,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَفَيْنَاكَ",
        "answer": "[We] are sufficient for you",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1283,
        "tlit": "kafaynāka",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 95,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَفَيْنَاكَ الْمُسْتَهْزِئِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be sufficient",
        "waznTlit": "kafā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 32,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلِّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulli",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَحَفِظْنَاهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْطَانٍ رَجِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلِّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulli",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ مَوْزُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّهُمْ",
        "answer": "all of them",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulluhum",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَجَدَ الْمَلَائِكَةُ كُلُّهُمْ أَجْمَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِكُلِّ",
        "answer": "for each",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "likulli",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَهَا سَبْعَةُ أَبْوَابٍ لِكُلِّ بَابٍ مِنْهُمْ جُزْءٌ مَقْسُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they had been",
        "pcklId": "590",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " رُبَمَا يَوَدُّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَوْ كَانُوا مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتَ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "591",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunta",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ مَا تَأْتِينَا بِالْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنْ كُنْتَ مِنَ الصَّادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they would be",
        "pcklId": "592",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they did",
        "pcklId": "593",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَأْتِيهِمْ مِنْ رَسُولٍ إِلَّا كَانُوا بِهِ يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكُونَ",
        "answer": "be",
        "pcklId": "594",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "yakūna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا إِبْلِيسَ أَبَىٰ أَنْ يَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَكُونَ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "595",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "takūna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ يَا إِبْلِيسُ مَا لَكَ أَلَّا تَكُونَ مَعَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكُنْ",
        "answer": "I am not",
        "pcklId": "596",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "akun",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ لَمْ أَكُنْ لِأَسْجُدَ لِبَشَرٍ خَلَقْتَهُ مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ مِنْ حَمَإٍ مَسْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَكُنْ",
        "answer": "be",
        "pcklId": "597",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "takun",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَشَّرْنَاكَ بِالْحَقِّ فَلَا تَكُنْ مِنَ الْقَانِطِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they were",
        "pcklId": "598",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 63,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ جِئْنَاكَ بِمَا كَانُوا فِيهِ يَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you would be",
        "pcklId": "599",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 71,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ هَٰؤُلَاءِ بَنَاتِي إِنْ كُنْتُمْ فَاعِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "And were",
        "pcklId": "600",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 78,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ كَانَ أَصْحَابُ الْأَيْكَةِ لَظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "but they were",
        "pcklId": "601",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 81,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ آيَاتِنَا فَكَانُوا عَنْهَا مُعْرِضِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكَانُوا",
        "answer": "And they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "602",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 82,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَنْحِتُونَ مِنَ الْجِبَالِ بُيُوتًا آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "603",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 84,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا أَغْنَىٰ عَنْهُمْ مَا كَانُوا يَكْسِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used (to)",
        "pcklId": "604",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 93,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عَمَّا كَانُوا يَعْمَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَكُنْ",
        "answer": "and be",
        "pcklId": "605",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "wakun",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 98,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَبِّحْ بِحَمْدِ رَبِّكَ وَكُنْ مِنَ السَّاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّعْنَةَ",
        "answer": "(will be) the curse",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1334,
        "tlit": "l-laʿnata",
        "frequency": 41,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكَ اللَّعْنَةَ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ل ع ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَعْنَة",
        "waznEnglish": "has cursed them",
        "waznTlit": "laʿnat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَلْتَفِتْ",
        "answer": "let look back",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1337,
        "tlit": "yaltafit",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ وَلَا يَلْتَفِتْ مِنْكُمْ أَحَدٌ وَامْضُوا حَيْثُ تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ف ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَلْتَفِتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to look back",
        "waznTlit": "yaltafit",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَوَاقِحَ",
        "answer": "fertilizing",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1343,
        "tlit": "lawāqiḥa",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً فَأَسْقَيْنَاكُمُوهُ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ق ح",
        "waznEnglish": "fertilizing",
        "waznTlit": "lām qāf ḥā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَلْقَيْنَا",
        "answer": "and [We] cast",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "wa-alqaynā",
        "frequency": 146,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ مَدَدْنَاهَا وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْقَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cast, to throw, to meet, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "alqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 71,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُلْهِهِمُ",
        "answer": "and diverted them",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1355,
        "tlit": "wayul'hihimu",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ه و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to distract, to divert",
        "waznTlit": "alhā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَسْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are not",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "lastum",
        "frequency": 89,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَعَلْنَا لَكُمْ فِيهَا مَعَايِشَ وَمَنْ لَسْتُمْ لَهُ بِرَازِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 89,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْسَ",
        "answer": "not",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "laysa",
        "frequency": 89,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عِبَادِي لَيْسَ لَكَ عَلَيْهِمْ سُلْطَانٌ إِلَّا مَنِ اتَّبَعَكَ مِنَ الْغَاوِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 89,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّيْلِ",
        "answer": "the night",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "al-layli",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِأَهْلِكَ بِقِطْعٍ مِنَ اللَّيْلِ وَاتَّبِعْ أَدْبَارَهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 84,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَتَّعْنَا",
        "answer": "We have bestowed",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "mattaʿnā",
        "frequency": 70,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ وَلَا تَحْزَنْ عَلَيْهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّتَّعْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to grant, to bestow, to provide",
        "waznTlit": "mattaʿ",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا",
        "answer": "and enjoy",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1367,
        "tlit": "wayatamattaʿū",
        "frequency": 70,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَتَّعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to enjoy",
        "waznTlit": "tamattaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَدَدْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "We have spread it",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1379,
        "tlit": "madadnāhā",
        "frequency": 32,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْأَرْضَ مَدَدْنَاهَا وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ",
        "rootWord": "م د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَدَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to spread, to extend, to prolong",
        "waznTlit": "madda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمُدَّنَّ",
        "answer": "extend",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1379,
        "tlit": "tamuddanna",
        "frequency": 32,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 88,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تَمُدَّنَّ عَيْنَيْكَ إِلَىٰ مَا مَتَّعْنَا بِهِ أَزْوَاجًا مِنْهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "م د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَدَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to spread, to extend, to prolong",
        "waznTlit": "madda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَدِينَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the city",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1380,
        "tlit": "l-madīnati",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 67,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَجَاءَ أَهْلُ الْمَدِينَةِ يَسْتَبْشِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م د ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَدِينَة",
        "waznEnglish": "the cities",
        "waznTlit": "madīnat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "امْرَأَتَهُ",
        "answer": "his wife",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1381,
        "tlit": "im'ra-atahu",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا امْرَأَتَهُ قَدَّرْنَا إِنَّهَا لَمِنَ الْغَابِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱمْرَأَت",
        "waznEnglish": "an evil man",
        "waznTlit": "im'ra-at",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَمْتَرُونَ",
        "answer": "disputing",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1387,
        "tlit": "yamtarūna",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 63,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا بَلْ جِئْنَاكَ بِمَا كَانُوا فِيهِ يَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمْتَرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dispute, to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "yamtaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَمَسُّهُمْ",
        "answer": "will touch them",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "yamassuhum",
        "frequency": 61,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُمْ فِيهَا نَصَبٌ وَمَا هُمْ مِنْهَا بِمُخْرَجِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to touch",
        "waznTlit": "massa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 56,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَسَّنِيَ",
        "answer": "has overtaken me",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1394,
        "tlit": "massaniya",
        "frequency": 61,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَبَشَّرْتُمُونِي عَلَىٰ أَنْ مَسَّنِيَ الْكِبَرُ فَبِمَ تُبَشِّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م س س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to touch",
        "waznTlit": "massa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 56,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَامْضُوا",
        "answer": "and go on",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1401,
        "tlit": "wa-im'ḍū",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 65,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَلْتَفِتْ مِنْكُمْ أَحَدٌ وَامْضُوا حَيْثُ تُؤْمَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ض ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَضَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go on, to continue, to pass",
        "waznTlit": "maḍā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَمْطَرْنَا",
        "answer": "and We rained",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1402,
        "tlit": "wa-amṭarnā",
        "frequency": 15,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 74,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَمْطَرْنَا عَلَيْهِمْ حِجَارَةً مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ط ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُمْطِرَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to shower, to send rain",
        "waznTlit": "um'ṭirat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْمَلَائِكَةِ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "bil-malāikati",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْ مَا تَأْتِينَا بِالْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنْ كُنْتَ مِنَ الصَّادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَائِكَةَ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "101",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "l-malāikata",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ",
        "answer": "to the Angels",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "lil'malāikati",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ قَالَ رَبُّكَ لِلْمَلَائِكَةِ إِنِّي خَالِقٌ بَشَرًا مِنْ صَلْصَالٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَائِكَةُ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "l-malāikatu",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَجَدَ الْمَلَائِكَةُ كُلُّهُمْ أَجْمَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُمِيتُ",
        "answer": "and We cause death",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "wanumītu",
        "frequency": 165,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّا لَنَحْنُ نُحْيِي وَنُمِيتُ وَنَحْنُ الْوَارِثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause death",
        "waznTlit": "amāta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَاءً",
        "answer": "water",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1428,
        "tlit": "māan",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً",
        "rootWord": "م و ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ه",
        "waznEnglish": "water",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw hā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 63,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَبِّئْ",
        "answer": "Inform",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "nabbi",
        "frequency": 160,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " نَبِّئْ عِبَادِي أَنِّي أَنَا الْغَفُورُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَّأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to inform",
        "waznTlit": "nabba-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 46,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَبِّئْهُمْ",
        "answer": "And inform them",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "wanabbi'hum",
        "frequency": 160,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَبِّئْهُمْ عَنْ ضَيْفِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَّأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to inform",
        "waznTlit": "nabba-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 46,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَنْبَتْنَا",
        "answer": "and [We] caused to grow",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1435,
        "tlit": "wa-anbatnā",
        "frequency": 26,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ وَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ مَوْزُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنۢبَتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make grow",
        "waznTlit": "anbata",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمُنَجُّوهُمْ",
        "answer": "surely will save them",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "lamunajjūhum",
        "frequency": 84,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا آلَ لُوطٍ إِنَّا لَمُنَجُّوهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنَجُّو",
        "waznEnglish": "was saved",
        "waznTlit": "munajjū",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْحِتُونَ",
        "answer": "carve",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1447,
        "tlit": "yanḥitūna",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 82,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَانُوا يَنْحِتُونَ مِنَ الْجِبَالِ بُيُوتًا آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ح ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ح ت",
        "waznEnglish": "to carve",
        "waznTlit": "nūn ḥā tā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّذِيرُ",
        "answer": "a warner",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-nadhīru",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 89,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقُلْ إِنِّي أَنَا النَّذِيرُ الْمُبِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَزَعْنَا",
        "answer": "And We (will) remove",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1457,
        "tlit": "wanazaʿnā",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَزَعْنَا مَا فِي صُدُورِهِمْ مِنْ غِلٍّ إِخْوَانًا عَلَىٰ سُرُرٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take way, to remove, to withdraw",
        "waznTlit": "nazaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُزِّلَ",
        "answer": "has been sent down",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nuzzila",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَالُوا يَا أَيُّهَا الَّذِي نُزِّلَ عَلَيْهِ الذِّكْرُ إِنَّكَ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "nazzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 62,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُنَزِّلُ",
        "answer": "We send down",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nunazzilu",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "nazzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 62,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَزَّلْنَا",
        "answer": "have sent down",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nazzalnā",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا نَحْنُ نَزَّلْنَا الذِّكْرَ وَإِنَّا لَهُ لَحَافِظُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "nazzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 62,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُنَزِّلُهُ",
        "answer": "We send it down",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nunazziluhu",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ مِنْ شَيْءٍ إِلَّا عِنْدَنَا خَزَائِنُهُ وَمَا نُنَزِّلُهُ إِلَّا بِقَدَرٍ مَعْلُومٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزَّلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "nazzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 62,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَنْزَلْنَا",
        "answer": "and We sent down",
        "pcklId": "174",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "fa-anzalnā",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلْنَا الرِّيَاحَ لَوَاقِحَ فَأَنْزَلْنَا مِنَ السَّمَاءِ مَاءً",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 183,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْزَلْنَا",
        "answer": "We sent down",
        "pcklId": "175",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "anzalnā",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 90,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَمَا أَنْزَلْنَا عَلَى الْمُقْتَسِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 183,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَصَبٌ",
        "answer": "fatigue",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1474,
        "tlit": "naṣabun",
        "frequency": 32,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَمَسُّهُمْ فِيهَا نَصَبٌ وَمَا هُمْ مِنْهَا بِمُخْرَجِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَصَب",
        "waznEnglish": "they are fixed",
        "waznTlit": "naṣab",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَنْظِرْنِي",
        "answer": "Then give me respite",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "fa-anẓir'nī",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُنظَرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give respite",
        "waznTlit": "yunẓaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "answer": "for the observers",
        "pcklId": "112",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "lilnnāẓirīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَعَلْنَا فِي السَّمَاءِ بُرُوجًا وَزَيَّنَّاهَا لِلنَّاظِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَٰظِرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "nāẓirīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "answer": "given respite",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "munẓarīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا نُنَزِّلُ الْمَلَائِكَةَ إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَمَا كَانُوا إِذًا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنظَرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "munẓarūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْظَرِينَ",
        "answer": "the ones given respite",
        "pcklId": "119",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "l-munẓarīna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ فَإِنَّكَ مِنَ الْمُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنظَرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "munẓarūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَفَخْتُ",
        "answer": "and [I] breathed",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1496,
        "tlit": "wanafakhtu",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف خ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفَخَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to blow, to breathe",
        "waznTlit": "nafakha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 19,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْتَقَمْنَا",
        "answer": "So We took retribution",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1512,
        "tlit": "fa-intaqamnā",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 79,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْتَقَمْنَا مِنْهُمْ وَإِنَّهُمَا لَبِإِمَامٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنتَقَمْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take retribution",
        "waznTlit": "intaqam",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْكَرُونَ",
        "answer": "unknown",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1517,
        "tlit": "munkarūna",
        "frequency": 37,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ إِنَّكُمْ قَوْمٌ مُنْكَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنكَر",
        "waznEnglish": "he felt unfamiliar of them",
        "waznTlit": "munkar",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَنْهَكَ",
        "answer": "we forbid you",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "nanhaka",
        "frequency": 56,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 70,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا أَوَلَمْ نَنْهَكَ عَنِ الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to forbid",
        "waznTlit": "nahā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 32,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَارِ",
        "answer": "fire",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "nāri",
        "frequency": 194,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْجَانَّ خَلَقْنَاهُ مِنْ قَبْلُ مِنْ نَارِ السَّمُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 145,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "answer": "mock",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1550,
        "tlit": "yastahziūna",
        "frequency": 34,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَأْتِيهِمْ مِنْ رَسُولٍ إِلَّا كَانُوا بِهِ يَسْتَهْزِئُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ز أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتُهْزِئَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to mock, to ridicule",
        "waznTlit": "us'tuh'zi-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَهْزِئِينَ",
        "answer": "(against) the mockers",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1550,
        "tlit": "l-mus'tahziīna",
        "frequency": 34,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 95,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَفَيْنَاكَ الْمُسْتَهْزِئِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ز أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَهْزِءُون",
        "waznEnglish": "mocks",
        "waznTlit": "mus'tahziūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلَكْنَا",
        "answer": "We destroyed",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1559,
        "tlit": "ahlaknā",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا أَهْلَكْنَا مِنْ قَرْيَةٍ إِلَّا وَلَهَا كِتَابٌ مَعْلُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "ahlaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 51,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَوْجَلْ",
        "answer": "be afraid",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1591,
        "tlit": "tawjal",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا لَا تَوْجَلْ إِنَّا نُبَشِّرُكَ بِغُلَامٍ عَلِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجِلَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to feel fear, to be afraid",
        "waznTlit": "wajilat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجِلُونَ",
        "answer": "afraid",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1591,
        "tlit": "wajilūna",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ دَخَلُوا عَلَيْهِ فَقَالُوا سَلَامًا قَالَ إِنَّا مِنْكُمْ وَجِلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجِلُون",
        "waznEnglish": "feel fear",
        "waznTlit": "wajilūn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوَدُّ",
        "answer": "will wish",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1596,
        "tlit": "yawaddu",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " رُبَمَا يَوَدُّ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَوْ كَانُوا مُسْلِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَدَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to love, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "wadda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَرْهُمْ",
        "answer": "Leave them",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "dharhum",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَرْهُمْ يَأْكُلُوا وَيَتَمَتَّعُوا وَيُلْهِهِمُ الْأَمَلُ فَسَوْفَ يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْوَارِثُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) the Inheritors",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1601,
        "tlit": "l-wārithūna",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّا لَنَحْنُ نُحْيِي وَنُمِيتُ وَنَحْنُ الْوَارِثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ر ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَارِث",
        "waznEnglish": "and inherit[ed] him",
        "waznTlit": "wārith",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْزُونٍ",
        "answer": "well-balanced",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1607,
        "tlit": "mawzūnin",
        "frequency": 23,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَلْقَيْنَا فِيهَا رَوَاسِيَ وَأَنْبَتْنَا فِيهَا مِنْ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ مَوْزُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّوْزُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and weigh",
        "waznTlit": "mawzūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُتَوَسِّمِينَ",
        "answer": "for those who discern",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1612,
        "tlit": "lil'mutawassimīna",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 75,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ فِي ذَٰلِكَ لَآيَاتٍ لِلْمُتَوَسِّمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَوَسِّمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will brand him",
        "waznTlit": "mutawassimīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَوْعِدُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) surely the promised place for them",
        "pcklId": "78",
        "rootWordId": 1626,
        "tlit": "lamawʿiduhum",
        "frequency": 151,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ جَهَنَّمَ لَمَوْعِدُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّوْعِد",
        "waznEnglish": "promises you",
        "waznTlit": "mawʿid",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْوَقْتِ",
        "answer": "(of) the time",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1635,
        "tlit": "l-waqti",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْوَقْتِ الْمَعْلُومِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَقْت",
        "waznEnglish": "are gathered to their appointed time",
        "waznTlit": "waqt",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَقَعُوا",
        "answer": "then fall down",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1639,
        "tlit": "faqaʿū",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا سَوَّيْتُهُ وَنَفَخْتُ فِيهِ مِنْ رُوحِي فَقَعُوا لَهُ سَاجِدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَقَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fall, to occur, to fulfill",
        "waznTlit": "waqaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاتَّقُوا",
        "answer": "And fear",
        "pcklId": "113",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "wa-ittaqū",
        "frequency": 258,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 69,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتَّقُوا اللَّهَ وَلَا تُخْزُونِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّقَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be righteous, to fear (Allah)",
        "waznTlit": "ittaqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "230",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-mutaqīna",
        "frequency": 258,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَقِينُ",
        "answer": "the certainty",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1660,
        "tlit": "l-yaqīnu",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 99,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَاعْبُدْ رَبَّكَ حَتَّىٰ يَأْتِيَكَ الْيَقِينُ",
        "rootWord": "ي ق ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "firmly believe",
        "waznTlit": "yaqīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكَ اللَّعْنَةَ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الدِّينِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ رَبِّ فَأَنْظِرْنِي إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ يُبْعَثُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "the Day",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 15,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْوَقْتِ الْمَعْلُومِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    }
]; 
export default words;